Contact

kate.lannon@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kate-lannon-17417614b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

CCRN

Critical Care

Cardiology

Certifications

Critical Care Registered Nurse (Adult) (CCRN-A)

Kate Lannon

RN at Tufts Medical Center, CCRN

Braintree, Massachusetts

Summary

I am employed at Tufts Medical Center in the Cardiovascular Center as a cardiac critical care registered nurse. I have experience in several areas including a cardiology step down unit, a high acuity cardiac intensive care unit, as well as electrophysiology laboratory administering conscious sedation during cardiac procedures. I have expertise in caring for patients requiring mechanical support devices and advanced heart failure therapies. In addition to Tufts Medical Center, I also work for Baim Institute for clinical research as a clinical specialist narrating clinical trial events.

Experience

Tufts Medical Center
Cardiac Critical Care Registered Nurse
July 2001 - Present (19 years)

Greater Boston Area

I am employed in a fast paced, high acuity cardiac intensive care unit caring for patients with cardiac and multi system organ failure. These patients often require mechanical support devices such as Impella, ECMO, Intra-aortic balloon pumps, CVVH and Left ventricular assist devices. I also have experience administering conscious sedation to patients undergoing cardiac procedures in the electrophysiology laboratory.

Baim Institute for Clinical Research Clinical Specialist-clinical review March 2016 - Present (4 years 4 months)

Greater Boston Area

Responsible for database management and event narrative preparation of patients enrolled in medical device clinical trials. These narratives are then presented to a CEC review board for adjudication.

Education

Villanova University Bachelors, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1997 - 2001)

Scituate high school (1993 - 1997)